infoinspired.com 2019-08-28

# Privacy Policy

We are furnishing below the privacy practices we follow at [infoinspired.com](https://infoinspired.com/ "Info Inspired") in a concise manner but that well covers all the requisite information.

The intention, our readers must know about our privacy practices by going through a few paragraphs that in a clear-cut manner.

First of all, make us clear that we collect some necessary personal information. Below are the details of the personal information which is being received and collected by us at **Info Inspired** and the use of it.

## Log Files

It’s a common practice that webmasters make use of the log files. At **Info Inspired** we are no exception.

We also make use of log files just like many other websites do. You may be curious enough to know what are the contents in these log files.

It contains information such as Internet Protocol addresses, date and time stamp of visit, browser used, method, protocol, referring pages, exit pages and status of the visit.

Why we collect all these pieces of information?

It’s because to properly manage our site we may require log files at some point. We assure you that we only use these pieces of information in the log files to that extend only.

By using log files we can analyze user trends like users movements around **Info Inspired**.

We may analyze these and also the user’s demographic information for the purposes stated above.

## Cookies and Web Beacons

Some websites normally use Cookies to remember or identify visitors via the browser. It may be for providing relevant content or something similar to that.

At this point make us clear that **Info Inspired** does not use cookies itself. However, we may use third party ads and affiliate links on this site. They may use cookies and web beacons to provide ads based on visitors’ interest. Find that details below.

## Advertising Privacy

This Site, infoinspired.com, is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.

AdThrive may use standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates.

We, infoinspired.com, publish interest-based advertisements on the Site. That means ads that are tailored to reflect your interests.

To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners, if any, will track your behavior on our website using cookies. The same is applicable to other websites across the Internet

A cookie is a file containing an identifier, i.e. a string of letters and numbers, that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

Cookies may be either “persistent” or “session” cookies.

  * A persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date unless deleted by the user before the expiry date.
  * On the other hand, a session cookie will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but please note that the personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, infoinspired.com, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third-party partners.

You can view, add or delete interest categories associated with your browser by visiting at [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

### For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in an EEA country, i.e. in the European Economic Area, then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.

If you would like to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site (infoinspired.com), you can contact at the following email IDs.

Contact Us: prashanth@infoinspired.com   
Contact AdThrive: info@adthrive.com 

If you would like to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences link at the bottom of the site (available in the EU).

## E-mail Address

If you make comment on this site or using the contact form to connect with us, it’s mandatory to provide your email address. We assure you that we will strictly maintain the privacy of such collected email addresses.

We may use these email addresses only to reply back. But make note that we are bound to provide any details required by govt. or legal authority at any point in time.

## Affiliate Ads Disclosure

We may participate in affiliate marketing programs. So we may include affiliate links on our website.

If a user opts to buy any product or services by clicking such links, we are getting a small commission.

This is necessary from our point of view to compensate for our ever increasing site running expenses. It’s up to the user whether to choose the product or services as we have no control over them.

## Cookie Management

All modern browsers provide privacy features as built-in or users can use third-party add-ons for this purpose. IE 10 metro is probably an exception to this.

For more information about cookie management about the browser you are using, visit the respective web page of the browser. Maybe the below links can help you in that direction.

1\. [Tips to Disable Cookies in Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en).

2\. [Disable Cookies in Mozilla Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences).

3\. [Delete/Control Cookies in Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies).

4\. Disable Cookies in Safari.

Visit the URL _http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/_ for information about how to opt out tracking.

Please note that this privacy policy is subject to change without third-party intimation. You may check back this page to see any changes occurred in the future.

Any query regarding our privacy policy? Visit this [contact us](https://infoinspired.com/contact-us/) page.

Last updated on 25th February 2019
